Isabela Monteiro

Email:isabelaluizi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/isabelaluizimonteiro github.com/Isabelaluizi isabelaluizi.ml

SUMMARY

A self-motivated, proactive and adaptable professional holding a Diploma in Web Development and BSC in Chemical Engineering. Strong knowledge in HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, SQL and Laravel. Problem solving and teamwork skills developed in 5+ years of experience in the Oil and Gas industry; advanced English and Spanish languages proficiency and full fluency in Portuguese. My career goal is to work closely in a team to apply and enhance my knowledges to become an asset to the company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML

PHP

JavaScript

SQL

Vue.js

WordPress

Git/Github

CSS

Laravel

SCSS

Bootstrap

Materialize

 MS Office -Excel.Word. **PowerPoint**

EDUCATION

Diploma Web Development InnoTech College, Calgary AB

Oct 2019 - May 2020

Projects

Okotoks Pizza: A fictitinal Pizzeria website built with HTML and CSS.

Website: https://isabelaluizi.github.io/

Tweeter: A social media website built with Laravel, Vuejs and MySQL.

Website: https://tweeterproject.ml/

Coffee Lovers: A coffee reviewer website built with Laravel, Vueis and MySQL.

Website: https://coffeelovers.tk/

Specialized in Renewable Energy Engineering

2018 - 2019

UERJ, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Bachelor in Chemical Engineering

2008 - 2014

PUC-RIO, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Degree evaluated as equivalent to Canadian degree by World Education Services - WES

International Exchange Program

2012 - 2013

Universidad de Cadiz, Cadiz, Spain

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE April 2019 – present

Formula Canada Immigration, Calgary, AB

- Translated documents from English and Spanish to Portuguese.
- Promoted and solicited orders for the sale of the Company's products and services.
- Provided administrative support related to clients referred for immigration services.

COMMERCIAL ANALYST

Aug 2014 – Dec 2018

REPSOL SINOPEC, Rio de Janerio, Brazil

- Developed projects aimed at future gas sales strategies in collaboration with asset and economic teams.
- Identified error in invoice by comparing numbers in the sales agreement contracts which resulted in savings of ~\$2M US for the company.
- Presented Natural Gas analysis to Repsol Board of Directors (local and international).
- Completed supply, demand, infrastructure, and price Natural Gas Market Studies by gathering and analyzing data from more than 10 different public and private sources.
- Created an automated Natural Gas flow model which included more than 9 thousand kilometers of pipeline. The model was used to analyze possible bottlenecks in the infrastructure, and it was presented and recognized by the Brazilian government.
- Negotiated gas sales with existing and potential clients which resulted in a signed sales agreements.
- Analyzed gas prices and developed a comprehensive study of potential profits and expenses for potential customers.
- Prepared quarterly Natural Gas, LNG and NGL price forecasts and reported to the economic team.
- Analyzed and tracked regulatory changes in the Brazilian gas market which resulted in a better understanding of the gas market trendings to support the future gas sales strategies.
- Managed the income and expense budget for the department which reported financial data.

GAS COMMERCIALIZATION INTERN

Sept 2013 - Jul 2014

REPSOL SINOPEC, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Trained as gas commercial analyst.

LAB ASSISTANT

Aug 2011 – Jun 2012

PUC-RIO. Rio de Janeiro. Brazil

Assisted university students with programming C++ in-class assignments.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Student Mentor

May 2019 - Jul 2019

Bow Valley College, Calgary, AB

Assisted college students with in-class typing assignments.